Digital Product Designer

Twisha Patel

Surat, Gujarat, India 🛇

www.twishapatel.in

Introduction

am a self-taught UX designer based in Gujarat, India. My journey in this field has been quite interesting. Even though I studied computer science engineering, I soon discovered that my real love is UX Design. It's the perfect mix of solving problems and being creative. I am dedicated to crafting seamless interactions that enhance user satisfaction and drive business goals. My background in computer science, along with my love for being creative and solving problems, inspires me to do well in the always changing field of UX design.

Education Background

B. Tech Computer Science Engineering - CGPA 8.65

BITS Edu Campus (GTU) | 2018 - 2022

Kendriya Vidyalaya Sangathan

Schooling

Skills

Wireframing and Prototyping Information Architecture and User Flows User Research and Usability Testing Illustration and UI Design Figma, Adobe Illutrator

Work Experience

Trinkerr Fintech

Associate Product Designer | Jun 2022 - Jun 2023

- · Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including a fellow designer and a senior designer, to establish a robust design system that streamlined the product development process and maintained design consistency across the platform.
- Conducted extensive user research to identify pain points and user needs, which informed the design decisions and contributed to a more user-centric product.
- Redesigned Trinkerr's web app, resulting in a user-friendly, responsive design that improved user engagement and retention rates by 30%. Our web-app design team played a key role in introducing new features, such as the watchlist page, Option Chain, Futures and Options trading, and an explore section, enhancing the platform's functionality and expanding its user base by 20%.
- · Utilized Figma to create interactive prototypes, allowing for thorough usability testing and early identification of design flaws, resulting in a 40% reduction in development rework.
- After the successful launch of the redesigned Trinkerr web app, our team seamlessly transitioned into a significant project, spearheading the creation of the TIQS broker platform from the ground up. This encompassed pivotal contributions in branding, defining the design language, and structuring the user flow.

Rupeek Fintech

Product Design Intern | Aug 2021 - Nov 2021

- Worked majorly on designing user-friendly UI and wireframes for their mobile app's revamp project.
- I had the privilege to make some contributions to the creation of their design system, known as 'Gravity.' Being involved in its early stages allowed me to gain invaluable insights and experience in shaping a new design system.
- I also collaborated with the design team and developers, and successfully handed off my work to the engineering team.

Azent Overseas Education

Product Design Intern | Dec 2020 - Mar 2021

- I designed user flows, wireframes, and high-fidelity prototypes for a new feature on their partner website.
- I also made some critical changes in the Information Architecture.
- I designed their expense calculator feature from scratch for the student website https://www.azent.com/expense-calculator
- Moreover, I also collaborated with one of the developers while working on a feature.